翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）
Now that we've implemented resize,
我们已经实现了 resize
our array list will work correctly.
我们的数组链表正常工作
So whatever we throw at it, it will properly handle the operations we ask it to do.
无论我扔给它什么，它都会正确执行操作
So let's do a little speed testing.
所以来做个速度测试
What I've got right here is a class called speed test Alist.
这有一个叫 SpeedTestAList 的类
It creates an Alist and then it adds 100,000 items to it using our addLast method.
它创建一个 AList，然后用 addLast 方法添加100,000个项目
I also have a similar test for the SLList from last time.
我也对上次的 SLList 进行了类似的测试
So I'll start by running that one.
先运行那个
I won't show the code because it's basically the same thing.
我没展示代码，因为它们基本一样
So when I do Java speed test SLList, we see it is very fast.
执行 java SppedTestSLList，非常快
In fact, I can use the Linux time Command to run it and see just how fast it is.
事实上可以使用 Linux 的 time 命令来运行，看看有多快
And we see that it is very fast indeed.
我们看到它确实非常快
By contrast, if we run the Alist speed test,
相比之下，测试 AList 的速度
we see it takes quite a long time-- three seconds.
我们看到这需要相当长的时间，3秒
Three seconds is actually quite a long time for a modern computer to add 100,000 items to a list
对于一台现代计算机来说
要将100,000项添加到一个链表中，3秒钟实际上是一段相当长的时间
and is obviously much worse than our SLList.
显然比 SLList 要糟糕得多
So why?
为什么？
Well, I've got a little puzzle for you to work our way towards understanding.
有个小谜题来帮助我们理解
So let's suppose we have a full array of size 100.
假设有一个大小为100的满数组
If we call addLast two times, the question is,
如果调用 addLast 2次，问题是
given that totally full array-- and we know it's going to have to resize twice--
考虑数组已满，我们知道它将不得不 resize 2次
how many total array memory boxes will we need to create and fill to actually accomplish what we want?
我们总共需要创建和填充多少个数组内存盒子才能完成任务？
And I have a bonus question here,
还有个额外问题
which is, what is the maximum number of array boxes that Java keeps track at any given time?
在给定时间内，Java 保持跟踪的数组盒子最大数量是多少？
And let's assume, in this case, that garbage collection--
让我们假设，在这种情况下，垃圾回收...
the thing where an object disappears--
对象消失的地方...
happens as soon as you lose the last reference to an object.
在丢失对对象的最后一个引用时立即发生
So maybe you pause the video and ponder this.
暂停视频思考这一点
So it turns out, for both of these, the correct answer is, in fact, 203.
事实证明，这两个问题的正确答案是203
Let's see why.
看看原因
So resizing twice requires us to do the following--
resize 2次需要做以下操作
the first time we resize, we create a new array of size 101,
第一次 resize，创建大小为101的新数组
we copy everything over, and that takes up 100 spaces here--
把所有的东西都复制过来，占据了100个空间
or we fill in 100 spaces.
填充100个空格
And then we finally fill in the last one.
然后填上最后一个
So that's 101 create and fills.
这就是101的创建和填充
We then repeat the exact same process, but now for 102.
然后对102重复完全相同的过程
And so in this case, we can say that the total number of array memory boxes that are created and filled is 203.
因此在本例中，可以说创建和填充的数组内存盒子总数为203
Likewise, the most array memory boxes that we have to keep track of at any given time is also 203.
同样，在给定时间内，跟踪的最多数组内存盒子也是203
You might say, at first, like, aren't all of these arrays around?
你可能会说，开始时不是这些数组都在吗？
But remember that during the copying process,
请记住，在复制过程中
as soon as we finished copying everything from this array to this one, we can throw this array away.
一旦我们完成了从这个数组到这个数组的复制，就可以丢弃这个数组了
So in the worst case, you'll just have two copies of the array laying around,
在最坏的情况下，你只会有2份数组的副本
and you won't have a whole bunch of them.
不会有所有东西
Harder puzzle.
更难的问题
Let's suppose now we have a full array of size 100.
假设有一个大小为100的满数组
And now, let's say we call addLast until size is equal to 1,000.
调用 addLast 直到 size 等于1,000
Roughly how many total array memory boxes will we need to create and fill?
我们总共需要创建和填充多少个数组内存盒子？
So ponder this question.
仔细考虑这个问题
I will now end the video in order to encourage you to actually do this problem.
我现在要结束这段视频，以鼓励你们真的做这道题
And there's the bonus question again,
这又是一个附加问题
and I'll see you in that video.
下个视频见
翻译：@隐秀_（seriouszyx）